### STEPHEN GARRETT DEWYER

### software developer | user experience designer www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

3136 Hennepin Avenue, #4 Minneapolis, Minnesota 55408 **stephen.dewyer@stephengdewyer.info** 248-766-8556

# software development and UX design skills

- Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Python, PHP
- JavaScript compilers, frameworks and libraries: SvelteKit, Svelte, Next.js, React, Vue.js, Express, Handlebars
- Artificial intelligence
- Stylesheet languages: CSS 3
- Markup languages: HTML 5
- Server environments: Node
- Development environments: Visual Studio
- Database management systems: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Application Programming Interfaces: Representational state transfer (REST), GraphQL
- UX design: wire framing, prototyping, user research, user testing, information architecture, user flows, user interviews
- Digital media: Adobe Creative Cloud, photography, videography, graphic design, brand identity design, animation
- Prototyping: Figma
- Web accessibility standards: WCAG 2.1
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- Geocoding

#### awards and grants

2014 - 2016

Knight Arts Challenge Detroit matching \$20,000 grant for ∞ mile John S. and James L. Knight Foundation Miami, Florida

2014

Detroit Chapter June 2014 \$1,000 grant for ∞ *mile* 

**Awesome Foundation** 

Boston, Massachusetts

#### career objective

An award-winning software developer and UX designer with over ten years of experience creating groundbreaking web programs for organizations. Experienced in working with multiple stakeholders to produce critically-acclaimed projects that have been featured in The New York Times, Artnet News and Detroit News. Effective at bringing together disparate parts of the community through multi-disciplinary projects. Interested in creating software that solves challenging problems for the public and businesses.

#### professional experience

April 2021 – present

# Founding Director, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Art in Tech Services Inc

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Created dynamic, accessible and responsive web programs including client collaboration software
- Works with clients to plan and achieve digital product goals
- Provides UX design for enterprise web programs
- Leads strategy for making digital products using advancements in art and digital technology

April 2017 – present

### Founder, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Public Arts Commission

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Leading the design, development and deployment for the organization's web platform that includes a campaign application management system, a voter networking and organizing portal, an endorsement management system and a searchable database of all the organization's endorsements
- Conducted user tests for web prototypes with Board of Directors and art experts
- Designs brand and media
- Works with Board of Directors to achieve organizational goals
- Responsible for overall direction of the non-profit, 501(c)(4) organization

February – May 2022

# UX Design Consultant (contract) Turnberry Solutions

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Created high-fidelity prototypes to personalize dental insurance plan shopping in the Federal Employees Dental and Vision Insurance Program (FEDVIP)
- Helped empower teams to produce great UX design for enterprise web products
- · Client: FedPoint

July 2013 – January 2017

# Web Developer and UX Designer / Co-Founding Editor ∞ *mile* (Infinite Mile LLC)

Detroit, Michigan

Collaborated with stakeholders to create brand and website

#### education

2009 - 2011

Master of Fine Arts (MFA) in Sculpture Yale University School of Art

New Haven, Connecticut

2005 - 2008

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) cum laude in Art History, Theory & Criticism Maryland Institute College of Art (MICA)

Baltimore, Maryland

### teaching experience

2015 - 2017

Lecturer

**University of Detroit Mercy School of Architecture Digital Media Department**Detroit, Michigan

2015 - 2016

**Special Lecturer** 

2014 - 2015

Lecturer

Oakland University Department of Art & Art History

Rochester, Michigan

#### websites created

• 2021 – present

**Art in Tech Services Inc** www.artintechservices.com

• 2017 - present

**Public Arts Commission** 

www.publicartscommission.org

• 2023

**Suzanne Conti Quilts** 

https://suzannecontiquilts.vercel.app

• 2022

**JoyFoodly** 

www.joyfoodly.com

2021 – present

web work portfolio

www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

 $\bullet$  2013 - 2017

∞ mile (Infinite Mile)

www.infinitemiledetroit.com

• 2008 – present

artist website

www.stephengdewyer.info

- Led a monthly online, Detroit-based art journal that published yearly print anthologies
- Directed editing staff and contributors
- Wrote successful grant applications
- Partnered with the University of Michigan Stamps School of Art & Design to produce two serial publications and conferences

#### technical training

2021 - 2023

### Certificates in UX Design, Software Development and Web Accessibility, Udemy

- Understanding TypeScript
- Machine Learning A-Z™: Al, Python & R + ChatGPT Bonus [2023]
- GraphQL by Example
- Svelte.js The Complete Guide (incl. Sapper.js)
- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL, Deno)
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Web Accessibility Training Course WCAG 2.1 Compliance
- The User Researcher's guide to UX discoveries

2020 - 2021

### Certificates in Building Web Applications, University of Michigan – Coursera

- JavaScript, jQuery, and JSON
- Interactivity with JavaScript
- Building Database Applications in PHP
- Introduction to Structured Query Language (SQL)
- Building Web Applications in PHP

2021

#### Certificates in Database Design, University of Michigan – Coursera

- Intermediate PostgreSQL
- Database Design and Basic SQL in PostgreSQL

2020

#### Certificates in Python Programming, University of Michigan - Coursera

- Python Data Structures
- Python for Everybody

2020

#### **Certificates in UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation**

- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- Mobile User Experience (UX) Design
- Become a UX Designer from Scratch
- Human-Computer Interaction

2021

#### Certificate in Leadership, University of Michigan - Coursera

• Inspiring and Motivating Individuals